# **JATIN GROVER**

21 Columbia Street, Waterloo, N2L 3K4 groverjatin17@gmail.com +1-437-984-8059

### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Versatile Senior Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience in various technologies such as Web Development, Data Analytics and developing Microservices. Versed with knowledge of ReactJS and Python languages along with good knowledge of Dashboard Designing and creating High-quality Web-Apps.

#### **S**KILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, Familiarity in Java and Spring boot
- · Operating Systems: Windows, Linux
- Query Languages: SQL, PL-SQL, CYPHER
- Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, ReactJS
- Tools: Neo4j, ELK Stack (Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana)
- Editors/IDE: Eclipse, VS Code, Anaconda
- Testing Frameworks: Selenium, Jest, Enzyme
- CSS Frameworks: SASS, Tailwind, Styled-Components

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Software Developer**

Amdocs - Pune, Full-time

# Nov 2019 – April 2021

#### Optima PLDT(Philippines):

- Developing new screen for the web-app that had multiple brands under the same banner. Pages included features like uploading documents and saving them into the database, Having a dark /light mode for the app.
- The website supported internationalization. Meaning that same app can support multiple languages. Initially upon entering the app, it autodetects user's local language and load entire website in that specific language.

• Writing Automation testing scripts to test the flow in variety of use cases. Calling mock APIs and showcasing failed Test Cases.

#### **Beeline Telecommunications:**

- Helped team in achieving daily Scrum tasks that include completing new User Stories. A lot of them had to do with developing new web pages that are part of a particular flow.
- Fetching data from a Microservice, wrangle the response and render them onto variety of front-end designs. The fetched data was to be stored in a module called Redux. Error Handling in case of unexpected response.
- Many tasks involved creating high quality responsive components that work on all types of devices in a uniform format. These designs include developing Tables/Accordions/Slider etc.

#### **Software Developer**

Standard Chartered - GBS - Bangalore, Full-time

# June 2017 – Nov 2019

#### **Auditing Tool:**

- Developed a Tool using Python script for PMs to rectify any missing documents in various Projects before Auditing.
- The tool parses through all the directories and subdirectories of a Project on SharePoint using Client-side API's and create a consolidated view of all the documents that are present or missing in the project. Then the report is automatically mailed to individual user for rectification.
- This effort helped secure all mandatory documents before final Auditing review. And most importantly, streamlined the process and removing human intervention.

#### Natural Language Processing:

- Huge amount to operational effort is spent to evaluate an incoming SWIFT MT599(free text format) message.
- Used R-Programming for analysis of free text messages and ELK Stack to prepare Dashboards. Search Guard Plugin for Authentication and User-Role based access to those Dashboards.
- Process involved Identification and Classification of various texts messages for MT599's into various Topics and creation of Dynamic and Interactive Dashboards for Operations team to keep track and reduce incoming MT599's.

#### Communique:

• Web Application for wide Community of Employees within the organization to find relevant skilled colleagues or Projects within the organization to seek guidance in their own BAUs.

 WebApp used External APIs from GitHub and Stack Overflow to verify the skill level of the users. This tech stack of the portal was based on ReactJS, Java/Spring Boot, SQL and Linux based VM

#### Trade Repair Analytics (Neo4j):

- Analysis of full lifecycle of the trade. From its point of origin till Settlement or Repair stage. S
  graphical structure rendered on the screen that helps in identifying relationships between
  various stakeholders.
- Neo4j is a Graph Database which helped in showcasing the graphical flow of data as Nodes and Edges.
- It has CYPHER query language as counterpart of SQL in RDBMS.

#### **Trainee**

Infosys - Mysore, Internship

# Jan 2017 – June 2017

#### **Training and Project:**

- Training in Python, Data structures and DBMS (Database Management System) in first GENERIC part of the training.
- Learned about Business Analysis in my STREAM training where we learned COGNOS (a reporting tool) and INFORMATICA (ETL tool).
- Final Project involved designing a Client Centric, Interactive and Dynamic Dashboard using COGNOS.

## **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION**

### **B.E Computer Science**

Chitkara University, Chandigarh

August 2013 – August 2017

#### **Awards and Achievements**

• Winner of Hackathon where goal was to create a Web Portal (RT-Controller) to Check/Create/Modify various Business Functions, Features and Scenarios under an Application. Trigger test scenarios from portal. Open JIRAs and log entries.

## **Hobbies**

- Mixed Martial Arts
- Backpacking

- Reading Quora or Articles on Medium
- Badminton/Working out
- Reading books
- Sketching Portraits
- Bhangra-Punjabi Folk Dance